[Saul grunting]
各位
Guys, come on, talk to me!
拜托 跟我说话
Habla, por favor?
Yo soy abogado!
Abogado! Abogado!
Oh. Crap, you already knew that.
糟糕 你们早就知道
Jesus, fellas?
老天 各位 不至于这样吧！
There's a better way to do this!
有人吗？
Hello?
[grunts] Ohh. Why are we-- why are we going off-road?
我们这是要去哪？
（磷）
Ohh! Ohh!
不管是什么事 能别去沙漠吗？
Whatever this is, can we please, don't do it in the desert?
除了沙漠哪都行！
Anywhere but the desert!
Oh! Oh, God, I'm gonna be sick.
天啊 我要吐了
- [groans] Ohh! - [tires screech]
Ahh. Ahh.
拜托 各位 这…
[speaking indistinctly]
This, we can-- we can fix this.
我们可以…有事好商量
不管是什么问题
Whatever the problemo, we can fix it with dinero.
都能用钱解决
Mucho dinero.
Mucho, mucho, mucho dinero.
拜托了
Come on, please.
One of you, just you talk.
你们有谁愿意聊聊 说话啊
Habla.
拜托了 以免铸成大错
Come on, before mistakes are made.
Come on, talk to me, guys, huh?
拜托了 大伙们 拜托了！别这样！
Please, come on, just tell me what you want!
想怎样就直说！
老天…
Geez!
Whoa!
不！不是的 不是我所为！
Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
No! It wasn't me!
是伊纳西奥！是他…
It was Ignacio! He's the one!
[video tape clicks, whirs]
[opening theme music plays, stops]
[clicking, whirring continue]
[ Jackie Chan Adventures plays on TV]
很好
不能把大麻籽和大麻茎扔进水槽
You can't put seeds and stems in the sink.
什么？
Put what or what?
大麻籽和大麻茎
不能直接扔下水道里
Seeds and stems.
You can't put them down the drain.
Uh, we didn't do that.
我们没扔
那这是什么？
Then what's this?
Regular sink stuff.
就是水槽里该有的普通东西
听着 如果你们要吸大麻
Listen, if you're gonna do this shit,
扔进马桶里冲走 别丢水槽里
at least flush it down the toilet, not the sink.
W-What're you, my mom?
你是我妈吗？我们不吸毒
We don't have drugs here.
Uh-huh.
你不相信我们
You don't believe us.
她不相信我们
She doesn't believe us.
你们一觉睡到大中午
You sleep past noon, you don't seem to have regular employment.
看起来也没有正经工作
而且这里闻起来臭气熏天
Plus, your whole place smells like a skunk's butthole.
还有 水槽里全是大麻茎和大麻籽
Also, your sink is full of stems and seeds.
听着 女缉警 我们没有吸毒
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Look, narca,
we're not doing drugs,
所以你别再…
so stop trying to cast, y'know...
aspersions.
恶意中伤我们了
Narca?
-“女缉警”？
-对 “女缉警”
Yeah. "Narca."
“缉毒警察”的女性版
The feminine version of "narco."
算是同源词吧？
Conjugate much? [laughs]
[Francesca sighs]
I gotta go.
我得走了 你们清理好后
把皮搋子放门外
Just leave the plunger outside the door when you're done.
但还堵着呢 伙计
But, uh, it's still clogged, dude.
You do it, dude.
那你来清 伙计
Hold up, where you goin'?
-你要去哪？
-嘿 女士
Yo, lady, we pay rent.
我们可是付了房租
你们可以的
You can do it.
就是简单的上下动作
就像你们经常做的那样
It's a simple up and down motion,
like you're used to.
[explosions on television]
[tense music playing]
（威廉姆欧克利律所
“相信经验 相信欧克利”）
好的
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
[telephone ringing]
[ringing continues]
[sighs]
Yeah.
喂？
[Gene] Oh, good. You're there. Great.
好的 你接了 太好了
Great.
非常好 应该没人盯着你吧？
Unencumbered by curious eyes and ears, I'm guessing.
Wouldn't have picked up otherwise.
-不然我也不会接
-好
Right.
Excellent.
非常好
Um, okay. Well, then.
好的 那…
[sighs] Lay it on me.
跟我说说
先给钱
[Francesca] First things first.
不 我们说好是事后给钱
No. I... I believe we agreed "after."
那我挂了
I'm hanging up.
好的 老天 我…
Okay! Okay, then!
Geez, I...
好的 如果你正朝着电话…
Okay, if you're... if you're facing the phone,
往右转90度 直走
turn right 90 degrees and, uh, walk straight.
然后会在土里看到几块碎掉的混凝土
You'll see some pieces of broken concrete in the dirt.
掀开那块形状像新泽西州的
Just pull back the one that's kinda shaped like New Jersey.
新泽西？
New Jersey?
戴红圆帽的
阿尔弗雷德希区柯克 随便吧
Alfred Hitchcock in a fez.
Whatever.
掀开后你会看到一个汽水罐易拉环
Just [scoffs] pull that one back,
and you'll see a, um, soda can tab.
上面绑着一根鱼线
It's got a fishing line tied to it.
跟着鱼线走 你会找到一根旧水管
Follow that line,
it'll take you to an old water line,
一直往外拽鱼线
我承诺的钱就在那里
and just keep pulling the string,
and you'll get what I promised.
Okay.
好的
很好 没少吧？
Great. Was it all there?
没被老鼠啃掉吧？
I mean, the rats didn't eat it or anything?
没少
It's all here.
[sighs]
好的 那个…
Okay, well, uh, tell me, how hot?
告诉我 有多严重？
-有多严重？
-对
How hot?
Yeah.
现在还有人跟踪我
Well... I still get followed.
虽然不像事发时那么猖狂
但我还是能看到他们
Not as often as when the shit first hit the fan,
but I still see them.
My mail gets opened.
我的邮件都会被拆开
家里的电话每次使用时都会咔哒响
My phone at home clicks whenever I use it.
所以大师买下农场后
情况没有任何改观吗？
So the maestro buying the farm, it didn't change anything?
No. If anything, it made it worse.
没有 非要说的话 就是雪上加霜
斯凯勒怀特签了协议
Skyler White got her deal.
现在就只剩你和平克曼在逃了
So the only ones left to go after
are you and Pinkman.
我听说他们在边境
找到了他的车 所以…
And I heard they found his car down by the border,
so, adios, dopehead.
再见了 大毒虫
Oh, so they're still into me.
所以他们还不打算放过我
那个…
Well...
那些美甲店呢？
Hey, what do you know about the nail salons?
美甲店都没了
Nail salons are gone.
什么？没了吗？全都没了？
Wha-- Gone? All of them?
对
Yep.
自动贩售机呢？
What about the vending machines?
-没了
-老天！
- Gone. - Jesus!
Ah, don't tell me... Laser tag?
别告诉我…激光标签呢？
也被联邦警察发现了
Feds found it all, Saul.
但怎么会呢？
But how?
明明藏得那么深！
It was shells within shells!
可恶
Damn it!
Damn it, okay...
好的
Okay.
嘿
Hey, oh, what if--
假如安提瓜和巴布达岛
Let's say there was an overseas account,
um, Antigua and Barbuda--
-有海外账户呢？
-虎鱼集团？
Tigerfish Corporation?
-什么？
-虎鱼集团 85万美元？
- What? - Tigerfish Corporation?
$850k? I gave it to the feds.
我交给联邦警察了
你做了什么？为什么要那么做？
You did what? Why would you do that?
已超时
[automated voice] Time has expired.
God damn it!
可恶！
你让我在一个虚假的集团董事会挂名
- Please deposit... - [Francesca] You-- You put my name
on the board of a fictional corporation.
我必须那么做 我真的是逼不得已
I had to give it up. I didn't really have a choice.
还有你该提前跟我说一声的
A-And a heads up would've been nice, by the way.
[coins dropping]
那么…
So it's gone?
没了 全没了
It's all gone?
那些狗娘养的全都拿走了
Those sons of bitches took everything.
除了你自己带走的
Except what you took with you.
我猜也不是小数目吧
And I'm guessing that wasn't chump change.
Yeah. Well...
好吧 那么…
那个…
Well.
看来就这样了
- Guess that's it. - Wait, wait, wait.
等一下 别挂啊 我刚又投了币
Come on, I just put more quarters in.
你能…我说不好
Can't you just, I don't know,
你能给我交个底吗？
gimme the lowdown.
-我全都告诉你了
-不是的
There's nothing else.
Well, that's not true.
看在我们这么久交情的份上
拜托 跟我说说
After all this time? Come on.
Just fill me in.
怎么…
What-- Um, how's Kuby?
库比怎么样？
不知道
No idea.
好吧 那修尔呢？
All right, how about Huell?
修尔吗？
Huell. [sighs]
他应该是回新奥尔良的老家了
I guess back home in New Orleans.
缉毒局以欺诈罪拿下了他
DEA held him under false pretenses or something,
我最后听到的消息是 他脱了身
so last I heard, he walked.
那就好
Good. Um, how about Danny?
丹尼怎么样？
或者伊莱拉？
Or, uh, or Ira?
他们俩有消息吗？
I mean, any word on those two guys?
你那里没网吗？
They have Internet where you are?
行了…
Well, just, come on, give me something.
拜托 跟我说说
总有点新鲜事吧
There's gotta be some news.
Uh, remember Bill Oakley?
你还记得比尔欧克利吗？
他换了立场
He switched sides.
他出柜了吗？
He came out, huh?
不是 他不是同性恋
No, he's not gay.
他现在是辩护律师了
He's a defense attorney now.
Huh.
我是说…
Well, I mean, what about you?
你呢？你怎么样？
How are you doin'?
我好极了
Oh, I'm just great.
Prince Rainier proposed.
雷尼尔王子向我求婚了
私人飞机周四要带我们去皇宫
The private jet is taking us to the palace on Thursday.
Yeah. Okay.
好吧 那个…
Well, I guess that's it, then.
看来就这样了
I did get one call. [sniffles]
事情平息后…
After everything went down.
我确实接到了一个电话
金
Kim.
她询问我的情况
Checking in on me.
No kidding?
你认真的吗？
Mm-hmm.
我们提到了你
Your name came up.
她问你是否还活着
Asked if you were alive.
她问了我的情况
She asked about me?
What did you tell her?
你怎么跟她说的？
Nothing.
什么也没说
但她问了
But she asked?
对
Yep.
[sighs]
好的 那个…
Oh, okay. Well...
Uh, I guess...
看来…
我们要就此别过了
this is goodbye.
- [receiver clicks] - Hello? Hello?
喂？
（电话亭）
（大帕特 全天提供早餐）
[clicks tongue]
（IRC接线员）
[beep]
嗨 我要查佛罗里达州一个号码
泰特斯维尔
Hi, I need a number in Florida.
Titusville.
棕榈海岸洒水公司
Palm Coast Sprinklers.
是在一条…
It's on a road, um...
It's named after a fish.
以鱼命名的路上
Uh...
Tarpon Road, right.
海鲢路 对
Uh, well, can you put me through? I'll--
你能帮我接通吗？我…
Say again, how much?
你再说一遍多少钱？好的
Okay.
[coins clinking]
[breathing deeply]
嗨
Hi.
我找…
I'm looking for Kim Wexler.
金韦克斯勒 她应该在那里上班吧？
I believe she works there.
[imperceptible]
[muffled shouting]
[grunting]
[grunts]
[machinery whirring]
（肉桂卷）
[brakes squeak]
[engine shuts off]
- [Marion laughs] Oh. - [chuckles]
又一个超搞笑的
Another good one.
嘿 小杰 你看谁来了！
Oh, hey, Jeffie! Look what the cat dragged in!
嘿…嘿 吉恩
Hey. Hey, Gene.
你妈妈在给我看你给她买的笔记本
Yeah. Your mom was just showing me
this computer you bought her.
但他买给我 我却不会用
Yeah, well, he... he got it for me,
and I didn't know what the hell to do with it, but, uh,
你看 吉恩教我了
look, Gene showed me.
- You... You go to the box up here... - [Gene] Mm-hmm.
找到这上面的搜索栏
然后输入“搞笑的猫咪视频 ”
...and then you type in "funny cat videos."
就是这么简单 “搞笑的猫咪视频”
I mean, that's it, just "funny cat videos."
[chuckles] These funny cat videos just pop up!
然后就会跳出一大堆搞笑视频
你来看看这段 来看看
Look at this one. Look, look.
[laughing] Cat eating an ice cream.
猫咪吃冰激凌 你能相信吗？
Can you believe it?
感觉就像《美国家庭滑稽录》
It's like America's Funniest Home Videos,
-但你是主持人
-那真是好极了
but you get to be the host.
Ooh, wouldn't that be something?
Wow.
嘿 小杰 去拿杯子
我们倒点荷兰杜松子酒喝 好吗？
Hey, uh, Jeffie, get some glasses, and we can pour the ol' Schnapps, huh?
Yeah.
好
[laughs]
我想着给她买台笔记本会是好事
I thought a computer would be good for her, you know?
It was on sale.
是打折买的
一点都…
Not a... big buy at all.
一点都不贵
我觉得这么做很对
Well, I think it's great.
“好好孝顺妈妈” 应该的
Treat your mom right, that's what I say.
嘿 玛丽恩 不如你自己看猫咪视频
- Hey, Marion... - Hmm?
How about, uh, we leave you to the cat videos,
and Jeff and I take our drink to go?
我和小杰带上酒去单独聊聊
你那辆车能跑吗？我想看一眼
I mean, is that car running? I'd love to take a gander.
Come on.
走吧
好的
Okay.
[door opens]
[door closes]
我发誓 我就买了笔记本那一个大件
I swear, the computer's the one big thing I bought,
而且也没花多少钱
and it's not even that much.
是一个打折的旧款
It's a... it's an old model on discount.
谁都没出去乱说 我没有 谁都没有
And nobody said nothing to nobody.
N-not me, not Buddy.
像往常那样过日子 就像你说的那样
Living our lives like normal, just like you said.
别说了
- Stop talking. - But I want to--
-但我想…
-杰夫 别说了
Jeff. Stop talking.
我需要你回答几个问题
第一个：你值夜班 对吧？
I need you to answer some questions.
First up, you have a night shift, right?
你是说出租车公司的夜班吗？对
You mean the graveyard shift?
At the cab company? Yeah.
What are the hours?
工作时段是什么？
有晚9点到凌晨6点
午夜到早9点 怎么了？
They got a 9:00-to-6:00, a midnight-to-9:00.
- Why? - Get on the 9:00-to-6:00.
你上9点到6点那个时段
然后我们得弄点巴比妥酸盐
After that, we need to get our hands on some barbiturates.
什么？
What?
开什么玩笑？
You're shitting me?
弄那玩意干吗？
What're we gonna do with them?
但你说过我们分道扬镳了 你说…
But you said we're done.
You said, "Cross to the other side of the street"
如果我看你迎面走来
马上换去路的另一边走
if I see you coming.
这么说我们要重操旧业了？
So we're back in business?
太好了
Oh, hell, yeah.
[glasses clink]
水手说：“布兰迪 你是个好姑娘
♪ The sailor said "Brandy, you're a fine girl" ♪
以后定会是贤妻良母
♪ What a good wife You would be ♪
但我的人生 我的挚爱
我的女人是大海”
♪ But my life, my love And my lady is the sea ♪
♪ Do da-dit-dooda... ♪
夜幕降临 酒吧纷纷打烊
♪ At night When the bars close down ♪
布兰迪走过一个沉静的小镇
♪ Brandy walks Through a silent town ♪
[speaking indistinctly]
爱上一个不在身边的男人
♪ And loves a man Who's not around ♪
她依旧能听到他说
♪ She can still hear him say ♪
♪ She hears Him say, "Brandy..." ♪
她听到他说：
“布兰迪 你是个好姑娘
Brandy!
♪ "You're a fine girl" ♪
以后定会是贤妻良母
♪ What a good wife You would be ♪
Con gusto!
但我的人生 我的挚爱
我的女人是大海”
♪ But my life, my love My lady is the sea ♪
♪ Do da-dit-dooda... ♪
[man chuckles] ** Doo doo-da doo-doo ♪
[man laughing]
- [coughs] - [scattered applause]
谢谢
Wow.
Ah. [sighs]
他真的唱了
He did that.
[karaoke singer sings "Summer Breeze" in the background]
- Ah-di-di-di-da-da. - [sighs]
那个…
Well. [clears throat]
看着兴登堡号沉没
That must've been what it would be like
一定就是这种感觉
if you watched the Hindenburg go down.
但比那更糟 对吧？
But worse, am I right? [chuckles]
但是心潮澎湃 对吧？愿赌服输
- Yeah, well, with gusto, right? - Gusto.
- A bet's a bet. - With gusto! [laughs]
心潮澎湃！
嘿 要不要再赌一次？这次加大筹码
Hey, what do you say we go again?
Up the stakes?
输家这次得光着膀子唱
Loser has to sing with his shirt off this time--
不行 不赌了 好吗？
拜托 我一次都没赢过
No, no, no. No more bets, okay?
Come on, I haven't been right once.
怎么了 小家伙？
Aw, what's the matter, wittle fella,
你一次都没赢过？一次都没有吗？
you haven't been wight once?
Not once?
嘿 能再来点花生吗？
Hey, can we get more peanuts?
[clucking] Come on, Viktor!
拜托 维克多 别跟个怂蛋一样
Don't be a wuss.
我不是怂蛋
I'm not a wuss.
没错 你不是
That's right. You're not.
你…你得相信自己 小家伙
You... You gotta believe in yourself, little buddy.
[clears throat]
拜托 我们再赌一次 再赌一次
Let's do one more bet. One more bet. One more bet.
- No. No more. - Come on, come on. Come on, come on.
不要 不赌了
不要再往我鼻子上塞柠檬
No more lemon wedges on my nose,
不要再耍硬币魔术
也不要再玩牙签拼图了
no more trick coins, no more toothpick puzzles.
I, I'm not good at this.
我不擅长跟人赌
维克多…
Viktor.
This is an easy one.
这次很简单
你要是先于我拿到这张百元大钞
钱就是你的了
Now, you grab the hundo before I do,
you get to keep it.
我要是先拿到 下一轮酒你请
I grab the hundo first, you buy another round.
只有一条规矩：我动了你才能动
Only rule is, you can't move until I move.
好 但我比你离得近多了
Yeah, but I'm... I'm so much closer to it.
这就是白送我一百块
It's like giving me the money.
所以你愿意赌？
So you want to take the bet?
好啊 我跟你赌
Yeah, I'll take it. [chuckles]
- [imitates buzzer] - Oh, son of a bitch!
混蛋
[laughing] Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh!
你真是不开窍
You lose, sucker. [chuckles]
[clears throat] Another round, good man,
再来一杯酒 朋友
这次还是我这位小伙计请
once again courtesy of my little friend.
好吧
- All right, all right. - [chuckles]
Aw. You're fun.
你真好玩
[chuckles, clears throat]
[with heavy accent] Gracias.
真是的
Ah-di-di-di-da-da- da-da-da-da-da-da-da.
[grunting]
[sighs]
You know, you're all right, Viktor.
你其实还好 维克多
Yeah, I just wish I knew how you did it.
真希望我知道你是如何做到的
[scoffs] Well, you see, I'm a man of many talents.
是这样的 我是个多才多艺之人
[clears throat] And you are a man of very few.
而你是无才无艺之人
[laughs] Kidding!
我开玩笑的
[laughs] Kidding. Maybe.
开玩笑的 或许吧
[chuckles]
Ah.
每次…每次她都会措手不及
Every time, every time, she'll never see it coming.
- [laughs] - Yeah.
Shh-- Yeah...
I need some night air.
我需要吹吹晚风
[breathes deeply] Well.
那个…
Easy.
慢点
看起来我们中一人的车到了
Looks like one of our cabs is here.
好的
Ohh. I'll bet you for it.
-我们打个赌 赢家上车
-不 不赌了
[laughing] No bets.
行了 听我所 很简单
Come on, now, hear me out.
It's simple.
别这么怂嘛
Don't be such a pussy, baby.
听着
Look... [imitates whiplash]
-怎么了？
-简单到家了
What?
Simple as simple can be.
把这排火柴放手背上别掉下去
保持十秒钟
Balance this book of matches on the back of your hand for ten seconds.
[Gene clicks tongue]
就是这样 然后出租车归你
我甚至会付车费
That's it, and the cab's yours.
I'll even pay for it.
你会给我一拳吗？
You're just gonna punch me or something...
No, I promise. My hands won't touch your body.
不会 我保证 我的手不会碰你的身体
我也不会把火柴从你手背上吹下去
And I won't blow it off the back of your hand.
真的吗？
Really?
My body will not touch your body
我的身体不会碰你的身体
也不会碰火柴
or the matches.
[scoffs, chuckling] Fine.
好 我总得赢一次 对吧？
- Huh? - I gotta win one, right?
好的
All right.
-没错 你总得赢一回
-好的
That's right, you do.
Okay, now.
跟我一起数
Count with me.
-十、九、八…
-九、八…
Ten...
- Nine, eight... - Nine, eight...
老天爷！
- Jesus! Jesus! - [laughs]
[imitates buzzer] Loser!
输家！
[laughs]
下次见了 朋友
I'll see you around next time, pal.
真好玩
This was fun!
维克多？
Oh, and, Viktor,
火柴送你了
you can keep the matches.
一个多好的姑娘
♪ What a fine girl ♪
♪ Do da-dit-dooda... ♪
[vehicle departs]
[sighs]
You call for a ride?
-你叫了车吗？
-没有 我不坐车
Nah. I'm good.
[laughs]
[snorts]
♪ Do da-dit-dooda... ♪
[laughing]
[coughing]
你没事吧？
You okay back there?
没事
Yeah. I'm fine.
肚子里有太多酒和坚果了
Got a lotta booze and, uh, nuts in my mouth.
你要是想喝的话 我这里有水
I got water here, if you want.
免费的
On the house.
[static crackles]
357号车 请汇报情况
[man on radio] Car 357, what's your status?
Yeah, car 357,
我是357号车
我距离送客点德尔玛大楼17号
大概还有10分钟车程
I'm about ten minutes away from my drop
at, uh, 17 Del Mar Place.
357号 送完客后去机场
357, head to the airport when you're done.
- [static crackles] - [Jeff] Copy that.
收到
[engine starts]
[brakes squeak]
你没事吧 先生？
You doing okay, sir?
没事
Yeah. I'm fine.
嘿 你可以走了
Hey, you can go.
我不会再给你小费
I'm not giving you another tip.
No problem, sir.
没问题 先生
[man breathing heavily]
希望你早点醒酒
Feel better.
[suspenseful music playing]
[door closes softly]
[camera shutter clicks]
（内布拉斯加州运营商许可）
[snoring softly]
[upbeat suspenseful music playing]
[camera shutter clicking]
（米德威地区银行
古德里奇县银行）
（账户）
[clicking]
[snoring softly]
[music stops]
[music resumes]
[music ends]
这里什么情况？
What the hell is this? [scoffs]
感觉就像詹姆斯惠尔的
公路巡演大篷车
It's like James Whale's travelling road show in here.
不管那家伙是谁
但这艘冰晶船绝对是行在路上
Whoever the hell that is.
The Crystal Ship definitely travels.
[Walter grunts]
抱歉 你说什么行在路上？
I'm sorry, you said the "what" travels?
冰晶船 我给这车起的外号
Crystal Ship. It's what I call this thing.
好吧 算了 别多说
All right. Never mind. Just-- No details.
我花钱雇他办事 不要节外生枝
We're paying him to do a job, let's just leave it at that.
No details? Fellas, that--
别多说？两位 你们付我的律师费
that money you put in my pocket,
并不包含此次差事
that doesn't just extend to this job.
但不管怎么说 保密特权还是有的
That will get you attorney-client privilege
on, on all matters.
我们不会多说
No. Details.
瞧瞧这装备
[Saul] Look at this set-up.
I-- What, you two drive around like Mister Softee,
你俩就像开冰激凌车那样到处转悠
卖冰毒球给那些好孩子吗？
scooping out drugs for all the good boys and girls?
我们不在这里卖毒
No, we don't deal from here.
我都说了点到为止
I said, "No details."
他站在一个制毒实验室里
Dude is standing in front of a meth lab.
他又不是傻子 肯定能猜到
It's not like he ain't gonna put two and two together.
He is on a need-to-know basis.
不该他知道的就别说
Oh. I didn't wanna show my face.
我不想露脸的 他需要知道这个吗？
Did he need to know that?
所以你们不只是分销
So, you're not just distribution.
而是一条龙服务
You're the whole freakin' package.
[sighs]
那种蓝色的冰毒是你俩制作的
You two actually make the blue stuff.
在这里？
Here?
[chuckles] That's amazing.
太神奇了
你能别乱摸吗？
Can you not touch--
瞧瞧这东西
[Saul] I mean, look at this.
我原来那条鱼可以把它当作度假屋
I had a fish that could've used this as a vacation home.
但你们用它生产货物 对吧？
But you're using it to make the goods, huh?
好吧 那是一个圆底烧瓶
Yeah. That's a, uh, round-bottom flask.
- Mm. - Right?
对吧？圆底？
Round-bottom?
It's a flask for distilling.
那是用来蒸馏的烧瓶
你要是打碎 就不是了
It won't be if you break it.
拜托了 把它放下
Now, please, put it down.
[Saul] Oh. [clears throat]
好的 所以如果你们制作蓝色冰毒
Okay, so, if you cook the blue stuff,
那说明你是伊戈尔 你就是…
then that means you're Igor and--
And that makes you--
你是海森堡
You're Heisenberg.
Wow.
嘿 告诉我
这一套设备的产能是多少？
Hey, tell me, how--
How much product can you churn out with a set-up like this?
够了 别再问了
No, we're done. We're done with the questions.
- Mm. - We ask the questions.
应该由我们来问你
你有一份工作 就这一份工作
You have a job, one job,
我还是不明白你要如何办成
and I still don't understand
how you're going to pull it off.
听着 等我安排妥当
我会在办公室给你们进行PPT演示
Listen, when I get all my ducks in a row,
I'll give you a PowerPoint down at the office.
但在那之前
把我们商量的东西拿来 好吗？
But until then, just... just bring what we talked about, okay?
别担心 我肯定能办成
And don't worry, I'm gonna make it work.
说定八万美元 我们再开始谈判
I'm taking the $80,000
as a starting point for negotiation.
都依你
Take it any way you want, that's the price.
价钱就是这样 我要坐副驾驶
And, uh... [clears throat] I'm callin' shotgun.
我来开车
I will drive.
好吧 当然了
Oh, yeah, sure, I'll just stand, I guess.
那我就干站着吧
[lowered voice] Dick.
混蛋
至少你不必
At least you won't be rolling around
像去年的圣诞节火腿那样
在送货车厢里滚来滚去
like the last Christmas ham
in the back of the delivery truck.
You know, I--
我膝盖不好
- I've got bad knees. - [Jesse sighs]
你们好像弄伤了我的旋转肌
Think you might've messed up my rotator cuff.
我不跟你们要正骨师的钱
就算你们走运了 她很贵的
You're lucky I'm not charging you for my chiropractor.
She's expensive.
但她什么都能调整
But she adjusts everything.
[engine starts]
[engine sputters, stops]
可恶
[Walter] Damn it.
倒车的时候得多给点油
You gotta give it some gas when you're backing up.
I gave it the proper amount of gas.
我给了适当数量的油
-估计这就是我们一动不动的原因
-车闲置太久了 会发动起来的
I guess that's why we're moving, then.
Look, it just was idling too long.
- [sighs] - It'll start.
[engine grinds]
你就该让我开车的
Oh, you shoulda just let me drive, yo.
听着 现在不会有什么区别
Look, nothing would be different in this moment
除非你吓得尿裤子 淹了引擎
except you panicking and flooding the engine.
[scoffs] Bullshit.
胡扯
两位 我喜欢刚才的
劳雷尔与哈迪喜剧氛围
Fellas, I was enjoying the Laurel and Hardy vibe,
但我不怎么喜欢比克森夫妇
but I'm not such a fan of the Bickersons.
好了 能送我回办公室吗？
Now, can you get me back to my office?
如果你们想让我施展魔法
我还有得忙呢
I, I got work to do if you want me to make some magic.
你只需要坐着等一会儿 仅此而已
We just need to sit a moment.
That's all.
车子闲置太久 燃油泵会过热
When it idles too long, the fuel pump overheats,
所以我们就让它冷却一下
and so we just need to let it cool down.
[Jesse sighs]
[coughing]
So.
那么…
拉罗是谁？
Who's Lalo?
Who?
谁？
[Jesse] Lalo.
拉罗 你以为是一个
叫拉罗的人派我们来的
You thought some dude named Lalo sent us.
你看起来像被吓破了胆
You seemed pretty freaked out.
我在道上没听说过拉罗这个人
Never heard of no Lalo on the street.
不是谁
It's nobody.
嘿 你要不要再试试？因为…
Hey, are you gonna try that again, 'cause--
还是几千年后
人们会发现我们被一场沙尘暴埋葬？
or are they gonna find us, you know, buried in a sandstorm
a thousand years from now?
拜托
Just please.
[engine starts]
Bravo.
好极了
I second that.
我同意
我给你们一个免费的建议
And let me give you two free words of advice.
去捷飞络保养一下
Jiffy Lube.
坐稳了
Hold on.
[knock on door]
[sighs]
[somber music playing]
[vehicle departs]
[exhales slowly]
[motor whirring softly]
["Tapioca Tundra" plays]
你在哪看到的？
《傻瓜个人理财》上？
[chuckles] Where did you read that?
Personal Finance for Dummies?
I mean, is it wrong?
是错了吗？
[chuckles] Yeah. Big time.
对 错大发了
[chuckles]
天才 不要把所有鸡蛋
放同一个篮子了
Don't put all your eggs in one basket, genius.
♪ Reasoned verse Some prose or rhyme ♪
好 我的车来了
Yeah, this is mine.
♪ Lose themselves In other times ♪
♪ And waiting hopes Cast silent spells ♪
♪ That speak in clouded clues ♪
-要不要来瓶水？
-好
- How about a water? - Sure. Thanks.
谢谢
♪ It cannot be a part of me ♪
♪ For now it's part of you ♪
♪ Careful plays on fields ♪
♪ That seem to vanish When they're in between ♪
♪ And softly as I walk away ♪
♪ In freshly tattered shoes ♪
♪ It cannot be a part of me ♪
♪ For now it's part of you ♪
♪ Sunshine, ragtime ♪
♪ Blowing in the breeze ♪
♪ Midnight looks right ♪
♪ Standing more at ease ♪
♪ Silhouettes And figures stay ♪
♪ Close to what he had to say ♪
♪ And one more time The faded dream ♪
（内布拉斯加州运营商许可）
♪ Is saddened by the news ♪
（信用卡）
♪ It cannot be a part of me ♪
♪ For now it's part of you ♪
[scatting]
♪ Sunshine, ragtime ♪
♪ Blowing in the breeze ♪
♪ Midnight looks right ♪
♪ Standing more at ease ♪
♪ Silhouettes And figures stay ♪
♪ Close to what he had to say ♪
♪ And one more time The faded dream ♪
♪ Is saddened by the news ♪
[imperceptible]
♪ It cannot be a part of me For now it's part of you ♪
♪ It cannot be a part of me ♪
♪ For now it's part of you ♪
[slurps]
[machinery stops]
["Hold on Strong" plays in the background]
想知道我的窍门吗？
[man] You wanna know my trick?
按自己的想法做事 别随大流瞎买
Play your own game,
don't get caught up with what the other guys are buying.
[Gene] Mm-hmm.
就像那句话说的一样
“潮水褪去时 才知道谁在裸泳”
Like the man says,
you never know who's swimming nude until the tide goes out.
[chuckles] I guess.
对 但是…
But, I mean, with this financial stuff,
但感觉金融圈有人在背后操纵
it feels like the game is rigged.
那些巨亨总是赢家
The big guys always win. [chuckles]
Well...
真希望我能反驳你 维克多 但我不能
I wish I could disagree with you, Viktor, but I can't.
欺诈行为绝对是存在的
There is definitely dishonesty.
但我觉得大多数人
都是遵守规则的玩家
But the majority, I believe, are straight shooters.
那些罪魁祸首…
Now, the... the folks responsible
for, uh,
安然公司、世通公司
麦道夫和他的同类…
Enron, WorldCom...
Madoff and his ilk...
[Gene] Mm.
地狱肯定为这些人预留了特别的位置
...I gotta believe there's a special place in Hell
for those people.
好
Yeah.
[clicks tongue]
但根据我的经验 那只是例外
But in my experience, that's the exception.
Y-You can't let a few bad apples spoil it for the rest of us.
不能让几颗老鼠屎坏掉一锅粥
其实…
- In fact-- - [alarm beeping]
[clears throat] Sorry.
不好意思
[Saul grunts lightly]
[sighs]
这些药看起来像是进口货
[Saul] Those look exotic.
我是过来人 维他命吃了个遍
I-I went through that phase.
I took every vitamin there was.
Hey, guess how many pills I took
你猜我为了防止脱发吃过多少药？
to try to keep the hair on my head.
- [chuckles] - Worked like a charm.
效果好得不行
那是什么药？
What are those for?
Cancer. [clears throat]
抗癌药
Oh. [clears throat]
Sorry.
不好意思
Uh.
情况…
Uh, is it, uh... is it bad?
情况严重吗？
反正不是良性肿瘤
Well, it ain't the good kind.
行了 继续喝 这杯我请
Come on. More drinks. This one's on me.
这里再来两杯酒
Get two more here, please?
嘿 我不该多嘴 但…
Hey, uh, it's none of my business,
but, um...
你能喝酒吗？
should you be drinkin'?
You only go around once.
人就这一辈子
你说得对
You got that right.
[glasses clink]
You sure you don't want to take this one, Vik?
你确定不坐这辆走吗 维克？
我可以等会儿
I can wait.
不了 你先走吧
No. It's all you.
好的
Ah, okay.
[man sighs]
[sighs softly]
[headset beeping, vibrating]
[motor whirring]
说吧 都是什么情况？
Feed me, what do we got?
-你记得吃鱼油了吧？
-吃了
[Francesca] You remember to take your fish oil?
- I did. - B-12?
-B12？
-吃了
- Did it. - L-arginine?
-精氨酸？
-全吃了 继续
Got 'em all. Next.
你应该在4点之前
为汉普尔提交上诉状
You're supposed to file that appellate brief for Hemple by 4:00.
糟糕
Crap. Um, hey,
嘿 你能放下旅行杂志代劳一下吗？
could you put down the travel magazine and help with that?
我不是律师助理 索尔
Not a paralegal, Saul.
总之 你12点半约的人到了
Anyway, your 12:30 just walked in.
好极了 让他们进来
Aces. Send him in.
Oh! Enter, Sunshine.
快进来吧 阳光
为我黑暗寒冷的世界带来一丝光亮
Cast some light into my cold, dark world.
["You're a Grand Old Flag" playing in distance]
[music fades]
[Mike sighs]
喂 我可是付着钱呢 对吧？
你可以随时跟我汇报
Hello? You're on the clock, right?
So give with the info anytime.
等你忙完之后
When you're done.
我可以多线程工作
No, I can multitask, please.
我不会跟你说的
如果你在…谁知道那是什么玩意
I'm not gonna talk to you while you're on...
whatever that is.
林登贝恩斯约翰逊当初边如厕
边听下属汇报工作
You know, LBJ used to have his underlings give him reports
while he was on the shitter.
Uh-huh.
好吧 要么我走人
要么我一脚踩碎你的脑袋
Well, either I'm gonna leave,
or I'm gonna put my foot in your skull.
[Saul sighs]
- [whirring stops] - Fine.
好吧
[grunts]
你应该体验一下
But you should try one of these.
[sighs]
你走路的姿势
就像被外星人扎过探针的科学怪人
You walk like Frankenstein
after he was probed by aliens.
[chuckles] I can get you one.
我要不要给你弄一个？
肯定能给你提气
It would do wonders for your chi.
[sighs]
好了 说吧
Let's go, lay it on me.
[sighs]
好的 首先…
All right. First.
里面是丹尼斯盖布勒太太
There's your Mrs. Denise Gabler.
她背着老公偷吃
She's cheating, all right.
[whistles] Limber.
真灵活啊！
Ha-ha!
至少我知道他们没发现你
Well, at least I know they didn't spot you.
要是发觉被隔着窗户盯着
怎能还有这么高的性致？
No one could stay that aroused
with your mug peeking through the window.
还有别的吗？
What else you got?
然后我跟踪了那个巴士司机
Well, next, I followed your bus driver.
提醒你一下 他脖子确实断了
News flash. He really does have a broken neck.
好极了
Fantastic. [breathes sharply]
这样我就好过多了 继续说
That makes my life much easier.
Keep it coming.
印第安纳波利斯的那个窃贼
拉斯基 在梅娜德坐过牢
Second story guy out of Indianapolis.
Lasky. Did a dime at Menard.
如果你想找一个嘴巴严实的大盗
这个人信得过
Now, if you're looking for a talent
who'll keep his mouth shut, you can trust him.
我觉得你值得留意一下他
I say he's worth keeping an eye on.
窃贼…
Second story guy, second story guy.
我笔记本上窃贼的数量
比高二舞会上的粉刺还多
I got-- I got more second story guys in my book
than pimples at a Junior prom. [chuckles]
那个叫海森堡的家伙呢？
What about, uh, that Heisenberg fella?
高中化学老师
High school chemistry teacher.
你在逗我 真的吗？
You're shittin' me. Really?
沃尔特哈特威尔怀特
JP韦恩高中的化学老师
Walter Hartwell White.
Chemistry teacher over at JP Wynne.
跟前学生 现在的瘾君子搭档
一个叫杰西平克曼的家伙
Working with a former student, current meth head,
one Jesse Pinkman.
Wow.
Uh, what else about the teacher?
关于这个老师 还有什么信息？
他得了肺癌
He has lung cancer.
老天爷！
Jesus.
难怪他一直咳嗽
That's why he can't quit with the coughing.
情况有多糟？
How bad?
晚期 他已经开始治疗
要接受更多检查 但情况不妙
Stage Three A.
He's in treatment, more tests to come,
but it doesn't look good.
听着 即便这家伙捡回一条命
我也不愿跟他打交道
Now, listen, even if this guy was gonna live,
I wouldn't go near him.
他完全是个外行
He's a complete amateur.
你看到的是外行
Well, you see an amateur.
我看到的是即将被塑形的80公斤陶土
I see... [breathes sharply] 170 pounds of clay ready to be molded.
即便他不是死于癌症
也会死于警察之手或被一枪爆头
Well, if the cancer doesn't get him,
it'll be the cops or a bullet to the head.
这是你的评价
还是那位“连名字都不能提”的
Is that your appraisal or is that what
"He-Who-Shall-Not-Be-Named" says about him?
大人物的评价？
他什么都没说 这家伙就是只小虾米
He doesn't say anything. The guy's small potatoes.
好的 我同意 我就是…
Yeah, okay. I hear you.
I just--
我有一种预感
I got a feeling about this.
这个叫海森堡的家伙有两把刷子
This Heisenberg guy's got something.
那可是上好的货
It's top of the line product, that's the buzz on the street,
道上就是这么传的
我就是觉得 如果管理得当…
and I just think, with the right management--
You know, years ago, I bought a Betamax.
多年前 我买过一台盒式录像机
好东西 上等货
Good product. "Top of the line."
专家说比家用录像系统好用
Experts said it was better than a VHS.
结果完全是浪费时间和金钱
Turned out to be a complete waste of time and money.
Hmm?
算了吧
Let it go.
[sighs] Guy with that mustache
蓄那种胡子的男人或许不够明智
probably doesn't make a lot of good life choices.
[chuckles] So, yeah, uh, the second story guy.
-好了 那个窃贼 梅娜德？
-对
- Uh, Menard, you said? - Yeah, right, right, right.
好的 他隶属于一个高级盗窃团伙
往加拿大贩售盗窃来的珠宝
All right, part of a high-end crew
fencing jewelry up into Canada.
这个叫拉斯基的孩子不走运
Now, the Lasky kid caught a bad break.
他躲在玻璃柜台里时 警察刚好经过
The cop was driving by just as he was ducking in a window.
他蹲了大牢 其他同伙安然无事
He did the time,
no one else on his crew went down. Solid.
他很靠谱
它们以穿越非洲的
大规模迁徙模式而闻名
[narrator on TV] Known for their vast migration patterns through Africa,
近两百万头角马每年旅行两千英里
nearly two million wildebeests
travel 2,000 miles each year...
[bottle thumps lightly]
使它们的迁徙
成为地球上最伟大的迁徙之一
...making their migration one of the greatest on Earth.
牛群在寻找新鲜的草…
[bottle thumps lightly]
The herd seeks fresh grass, following the rain through Kenya and Tanzania.
Gathering each year to prepare for the journey,
one that's been taking place for a million years.
[Gene sighs]
The voyage is not easy.
While traveling, the herd must stay well fed, rested
在旅途中，鹿群必须吃饱
休息，远离疾病
and free of disease or be left behi--
否则就会被遗弃…
再来几下 洗牌 女士们
[class instructor] Couple more. And shuffle, ladies.
就这样
Just like that.
现在L踏步
- [headset beeping, vibrating] - Now L step.
Four times.
四次
难以置信
Fabulous!
让我看到你玩得开心
Let me see you having fun.
喂？
Yeah.
[clears throat]
W-- Uh.
等一下 你什么意思？
What do you mean?
他…什么？
He what?
让他马上回车库
Tell-- Tell him to get his ass back to the garage right now.
[Marion laughs]
你真是个小可爱
You cutie-patootie.
[sighs]
真是大千世界 无奇不有
You think you've seen everything. [laughs]
[dog barking in distance]
小猫 对不起
[woman talking indistinctly on headphones]
小猫
[barking continues]
让那只狗别叫唤了 赶紧进来
[Gene] Shut that goddamn dog up and get back in here.
[Buddy speaking indistinctly]
没关系 好孩子 我知道
[vehicle door closes]
进来
[Gene] Get in.
你在逗我吗？真的在逗我吗？
You're kidding me. You're absolutely kidding me.
-抱歉 我没办法…
-你知道我为了
I'm sorry, man. I couldn't--
Do you know how much time, how much effort,
找到完美的目标
花费了多少时间和精力吗？
I put into finding the perfect mark?
我得排除那些
家里有老婆和亲人的笨蛋
I have to weed through all these saps
who have wives and families at home,
才能找到一个有钱独居的人…
find somebody who's alone with money,
and, what, so you can just wimp out?
然后呢？让你临阵退缩吗？
那家伙得了癌症
我在他口袋里发现了药片
- The guy has cancer, man. - [sighs]
I found pills in his pocket.
好吗？就跟我爸当初
治疗胰腺癌时吃的一样
Okay? The same ones my dad took.
For, like, pancreatic cancer.
所以得癌症的人就不可能是混蛋吗？
So? A guy with cancer can't be an asshole?
[scoffs] Believe me, I speak from experience.
相信我 我这是经验之谈
我不能偷癌症病人的钱 抱歉
I can't rip off a guy with cancer. I'm sorry.
你知道我们偷过的多少人
都有悲惨的经历吗？
Do you know how many of the suckers we've ripped off have sob stories?
每个人都有
Every single one of them.
再说了 他们要等好几个月
才明白被偷了
Besides, it'll be months
before they even realize they've been taken.
这家伙到时候早死了
所以你给我回车上去
This guy will already be dead.
So, please, get back in your truck,
返回那里 完成工作
go back to the house, and finish the job.
不行 我做不到
No, man. I can't do that.
我不能
I can't.
好吧 我理解
[Gene] Look, all right. [chuckles] I get it.
你克服一下 好吗？拜托了 相信我
You get over it, okay?
Please, believe me. Y--
你很快会把这件事忘到九霄云外
Before you know it, you forget all about it.
快去吧
Go.
听着 我们干得不错 对吧？
听我说完 好吗？
Well, l-look, we're doing really well, right?
Hear me out, okay? I mean, we're rolling in cash.
财源滚滚来
-就放过这个人吧
-你说了不算
We can just let this one go.
Not your call.
[scoffs] Yeah, but I, I pulled the tape when I left.
但是我离开时撕掉了胶带
门已经锁上了
The door's locked.
我们进不去了
We couldn't get back in even if we wanted to.
闭嘴！
[grunts]
杰夫 拜托 帮我说句话
Jeff, come on, man, back me up here.
Huh?
我说不好 我觉得你俩都有理
Oh, well... I, I don't know.
I mean, I can see both sides, kinda.
算了 你被解雇了
把照相机给我走人吧
You know, forget it. You're fired. Just go.
Just gimme the camera and go.
[sighs] Fine.
-好吧
-好！走吧！我们不需要你
Good. Go. We don't need you.
我知道不必嘱咐你
但你既然如此不专业
And I know I don't need to tell you this,
but since you're such a goddamned amateur,
我还是多说一句
I will anyway.
给我闭紧嘴巴
Keep your mouth shut.
[door creaks]
要是想办事的话 我们得走了
If we're gonna do this, we should leave now.
我们真要回去吗？
We're really gonna go back there?
我刚怎么说的？
What'd I just say?
杰夫 你到底干不干？
Jeff, are you in or out?
（阿尔伯克基同位素队）
什么？
[Gene] What?
I'm down for this. I am.
我是想去 真的 但是…
- But, uh... - But what?
但是什么？
这家伙什么时候吃的药？
我们何时下的药？
What time did the guy take the drugs?
We gave it to him, what? Three hours ago?
三个小时前？
我都不知道他有没有喝完
I don't even know if he finished it.
-他现在或许已经醒了
-没关系
He might be awake by now.
Don't worry about it.
-好吧
-我说了没关系
Yeah, but--
I said don't worry about it.
不会有事的
It'll be fine.
That's it. Right there.
到了 就是那里
[sighs] Come back and get me in 20 minutes.
20分钟后回来接我
慢慢开 像是在寻找客人一样
Just roll up slow, like you're picking up a fare.
不会有事的
It'll be fine. Relax.
放松
[indistinct chatter]
（JP韦恩高中年度科学展
马上报名！）
[somber music playing]